# **OLOWOJAYE ORIMISAN RUFUS**

+234 8130686597 | Ife, Osun State, Nigeria olowojaye.public@gmail.com| https://olowojaye.github.io

## **SUMMARY**

Software Developer with experience in developing responsive and accessible web applications to meet business needs. Proficient with React, NodeJS and the NextJS framework. A first-class engineering graduate and thorough learner open to learning new technologies as problem solutions may require.

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

2022 Responsive Web Design Developer Certification

<u>Issued by freeCodeCamp</u>

2021 IBM Data Science Professional Certificate

Issued by Coursera

#### **EDUCATION**

2014-2019 Bachelor of Science in Mechanical Engineering

Obafemi Awolowo University, Ile-Ife, Nigeria

First Class Honors

## WORK EXPERIENCE

2022-Current Full Stack Developer

Max Engineering Tutorials, Obafemi Awolowo University, Nigeria

- Developed and maintain the front end and back end of organization's websites https://maxedu.ng and https://unidrills.com.
- Coordinate the design team to deliver functionalities with optimum user experience.

### 2016-Current

### **Lead Tutor**

Max Engineering Tutorials, Obafemi Awolowo University, Nigeria

- Founded organization to mitigate poor performance in undergraduate engineering courses at the university, reaching averagely 150 students each session.
- Instruct 100+ students on Computer Programming, Engineering Mechanics, and Mathematical Methods, with over 95% achieving target scores every semester.
- Coordinate 12 team members and manage resources to achieve set goals at the minimum cost and inconvenience to students' regular school work.

## **SKILLS**

Web Development: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript
Web Technology Stack: ReactJS, NodeJS, NextJS
Styling: SASS, Bootstrap, TailwindCSS
Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Version Control: Git

Programming: Python, Java

Data Science and AI: Python, TensorFlow, SQL

Cloud: IBM Cloud, AWS

Others: Teamwork, Effective Communication

## **AWARDS**

2015-2019 Agbami Special Medical and Engineering Professionals Scholarship Award

 $A\ sessional\ scholarship\ for\ select\ Medical\ and\ Engineering\ under graduates,\ conditioned\ on$ 

sustained academic standing of at least 60% of the university CGPA rating.

2014 Dean's Honors List, Faculty of Technology, Obafemi Awolowo University, Ile-Ife

In recognition of outstanding academic performance of at least 4.50/5.0 GPA for the semester.